Guide to the Hank Miller Papers WAG.176
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Hank Miller Papers
1953-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Miller, Hank
WAG.176
34.25 Linear Feet in 17 record cartons, 9 flat oversize boxes, 4 manuscript boxes, and 1 half manuscript box.
2 audiocassettes
1 videocassettes (vhs-c)
1 sound discs (vinyl)
The Hank Miller Papers includes the materials of long-time Local 424 general president, Hank Miller. He was with the union for almost 50 years, through its many iterations. Initially a union of truck drivers, Local 424 changed several times and came to represent workers from other lines of work, such as industry and public service. It began in the 1950s as the Packing of Grain, Fertilizers and Processors of Allied Food Industries, Independent Local 424 and had many different names until 1999 when it merged with Local 1102 RWDSU UFCW. This collection contains materials related to the history of Local 424, from its formation to its merger (and the aftermath thereof). Materials include meeting minutes and agendas, administrative and financial documents, correspondence and memos, membership ledgers, daily planners, notepads, newspaper clippings and research files, negotiations materials, contracts, newsletters, memoir manuscripts, photographic prints and negatives, publications, audiocassette tapes, a compact VHS tape, buttons, t-shirts, and other artifacts.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Hank Miller in 2002. The accession number 2002.027 is associated with this gift.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials related to Local 424, an independent union. Initially a union of truck drivers, Local 424 changed several times and came to include industrial workers and public service employees. Materials include meeting minutes and agendas, administrative and financial documents, correspondence and memos, membership ledgers, daily planners, notepads, newspaper clippings and research files, negotiations materials, contracts, newsletters, memoir manuscripts, photographic prints and negatives, publications, audiocassette tapes, a compact VHS tape, buttons, t-shirts, and other artifacts. The materials cover the history of Local 424 from its formation to its merger (and the aftermath thereof) with Local 1102 in 1999.
Biographical Note
The Hank Miller Papers includes the materials of long-time Local 424 general president, Hank Miller. He was with the union for almost 50 years, through its many iterations. Initially a union of truck drivers, Local 424 changed several times and came to represent workers from other lines of work, such as industry and public service. It began in the 1950s as the Packing of Grain, Fertilizers and Processors of Allied Food Industries, Independent Local 424 and had many different names until 1999 when it merged with Local 1102 RWDSU UFCW.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Truck drivers -- Labor unions -- United States.; Food service employees -- Labor unions -- United States.; Labor unions -- Organizing.; Labor unions -- Officials and employees.; Labor unions -- New York (State); Labor unions -- Elections.; Correspondence.; Contracts.; Collective labor agreements.; Clippings (information artifacts); Notebooks.; Collective bargaining -- New York (State); Buttons (information artifacts).; Miller, Hank; International Brotherhood of Teamsters
- Meeting Agendas and Minutes, Notices, Financial Documents, Correspondence and Memos, Ledger, and Contracts, 1959, 1963-1999 (Box 1)
- Negotiations Materials, Newspaper Clippings, Newsletters, and Speeches, 1964-2000 (Box 2)
- Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Newsletters and Organizing Leaflets, Ledger Pages, and Administrative Materials, 1966, 1979-1999 (Box 3, Box 31)
- Administrative Materials, Photographs, Scrapbook Pages, Autobiography Manuscript, Newspaper Clippings, and Negotiations Materials, 1959-1971, 1990-1998 (Box 4)
- Ledgers, Newspaper Clippings, and Correspondence, 1966-2000 (Box 5)
- Membership Dues Ledgers, 1967-1976 (Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9)
- Membership Dues Ledgers and Picket Signs, 1977-1980 (Box 10)
- Newspaper Clippings, Negotiations Materials, and Meeting Minutes, 1953-2000 (Box 11)
- Financial Materials, Negotiations Materials, Notepads, Newsletters, a Vinyl Record, and Newspaper Clippings, 1968-1969, 1976, 1980-2000 (Box 12)
- Notepads, Negotiations Materials, Memoir Manuscript, and Research Files, 1964-1965, 1985-1986, 1992-2004 (Box 13)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1990, 1998 (Box 14)
- Newspaper Clippings and Negotiations Materials, 1955-1965, 1982-2001 (Box 15)
- Negotiations Materials, Notepads, Newspaper Clippings, and Meeting Ledgers, 1958-1997 (Box 16)
- Negotiations Materials, Newspaper Clippings, Newsletters, and Financial Materials, 1973-1996 (Box 17)
- Contracts and Negotiations Materials, 1974-1985 (Box 18)
- Contracts, Negotiations Materials and Financial Materials, 1970-1984 (Box 19)
- Financial Materials, Newspaper Clippings, Research Materials, 1981 Daily Planner, and Newsletters, 1965-2002 (Box 20)
- Daily Planners, 1974-1980, 1982-1984 (Box 21)
- Daily Planners, 1985-1994 (Box 22)
- Daily Planners and Local 424 Benefits, 1984, 1995-1999 (Box 23)
- Notepads, Administrative and Financial Materials, and Negotiations Materials, 1984-2000 (Box 24)
- Notepads, Meeting Minutes, Newsletters, and Administrative and Financial Materials, 1963-1966, 1978-2001 (Box 25)
- Notepads, Booklets, Leaflets, Photographs, and Benefits Materials, 1959-2000 (Box 26)
- Benefits and Agreement Materials, 1997 (Box 27)
- Booklets and Other Publications, 1952-1991 (Box 29)
- Artifacts – Nameplate and Plaque, circa 1980s (Box 28)
- Artifacts – T-Shirts and Buttons, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 30)
- Audiovisual Material – Majestic, 3-23-87, 1987 (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
- Audiovisual Material – "Union organizers fees...", circa 1980s (Box Shared Tamiment 067)
- Audiovisual Material – Union Tape II, 3/9 Board Meeting, circa 1980-1999 (Box Shared Tamiment 067)